I hope with this session here you're
excited. We're going to have concepts.
We're going to have codes. Uh my
intention is to go through the concepts
first and then exploring on codes. So if
you have like any questions raise that
up. Uh probably going to rely on on
reactor to facilitate that. But bring
your questions perhaps if I don't get to
answer them as they they come uh through
coding. We're going to be uh exploring
that in details. So let's start in here
with AI agents and workflows. Um we can
compare like them. Let's do like a
comparison. For example, with workflows,
it's always uh predictable, right? We
can't say and compare like a workflow
being a train on tracks. So it's never
going to derail you know that starts at
some point is going to finish at some
point and it goes as uh we can predict.
So there are we we say like in technical
terms that they are deterministic
because we know like we can predict we
we have a predefined path. It is
repeatable. So they can execute multiple
times and they don't change and you can
do it's auditable as well because you
have like traceability and you see
exactly what happened at that moment in
time. So that's like the characteristics
of like a workflow when we look like at
AI agents they are a little bit
different because they're very dynamic.
So we can compare them like a taxi
navigating traffic. So if you are
visualizing that like there's traffic in
the and things are just completely
stuck. Agents are going to find a way to
deviate or find alternatives, right?
Alternative routes. So we're looking
here. They're dynamic. They're adaptive.
They are made for open-ended problems
like ambiguous problems. So when we have
um Microsoft agent uh framework
workflows, we're basically combining
them together.
And so we're putting like so we have the
workflows for the rails and the agents
for the dynamic decisions that happen
inside the workflow. So regardless on
where the the uh uh the step of the
execution the AI agent is you know
that's going to have an input an action
is going to happen and there will be an
output right to then something else
occurs finalize or having like a
continuity of our execution but we bring
like agents to behave and combining with
uh uh uh a predictable uh pathway.
There are some building blocks on when
we look at the different piece of how
the the workflows
uh behave within the agent framework.
We're calling them like here like the
major ones that where we have our code
or logic the executors. So they're rack
logic uh any sort of logic but you
expect some sort of input and an output
and they should be typed so you you know
exactly what's coming in and exactly
what's going out.
And here we have like this example of
two executors and we have something here
in between connecting them. We call them
edges. And this is a direct connection
that allows us to uh take the outputs of
one executor and connecting to the input
uh to the next executor
and well there's like full type safety.
They get validated at compile time. So
which is one of the greatest things
about uh agent framework flows. And
there are like life cycle signals,
right? Those events that are triggered
when something happens. For example, our
executor that's been invoked or maybe
our executor has finished. So we have
this event of completed perhaps we're
looking like the whole workflow uh
process like where we have workflow
started, workflow output. So we have
like events where we can listen to and
depending on what you're implementing
you could have like any particular uh
action from it
and then we have those five
orchestration patterns. So those ones
are the foundations really for
uh the different sort of orchestrations
that you could combine or you could have
because they help us defining some sort
of behaviors and for example where have
like sequential pattern that you know
that the agents they're going to be
executing one thing one let's say one
task after the other.
We have the concurrence where the agents
can execute tasks in parallel. The
handoff, it's when we have an agent
that's more like a coordinator that
transfer control to another uh
agent. So just transferring context.
The beauty of the agent framework flow
is that the context it's all managed for
us. So we don't need to worry about
that. you just need to plug and play uh
the the workflows together.
We have the group chats where we allow
we have like these agents talking to
each other and they share a conversation
and the magentic one where it's a more
specialized
sort of orchestration where there's a
manager uh a sort of like an agent that
coordinates the actions that are going
to occur. But not only that, there's a
planning in that's executed by this
manager. The manager tells who exactly
needs to perform what. So this two here
are new ones. The hand off they're like
with all the integration
um mechanisms to do something like that.
But those are uh I would say are going
to become more popular with agentic AI
agentic workflows.
So and you can combine them. So they can
can be combined and should be combined
according to your requirements.
Uh before I jump to that one thing I I
want to mention is that this is part of
AI 500 uh certification. I just put a
label here because I was uh part of like
having like this exam and I noticed that
it's part of the the my studies. So
there's a particular
um topic where all of the orchestration
patterns are approached. So we are
covering here part of the exam as well.
And as I said that we can combine those
orchestration patterns here for example
where we have this input and the end the
output. But you can see that we have a
combination of sequential with
concurrent flows because as things
finish in here like the parallel
execution they are aggregated. We
basically have one two three steps in
here. This is a another well it's a
pattern called like uh fan out fan in
but they're basically composed by
sequential and concurrent
uh orchestration patterns basically have
like this entry agents parallel
specialists and this aggregator. So you
you're free to combine them just to
match like the your requirements.
One thing that's important for us as
developers is that
uh everything that I'm going to be
approaching here is from code. So I'm
we're going to be approaching .NET. So I
have a samples available. But when you
run those workflows, if you don't have a
visual way to see what's happening, you
simply don't know uh what happened.
you're only going to identify what
happened by looking at logs, right? Open
telemetry and see exactly like the
traces that happen. Um, some developers
might be okay with that. Others prefer
like a visual way. And then we have Dev
UI that's going to assist you to run and
debug like those workflows visually. So
we have a web front end that helps us
visualizing what's in there. So it's a
web UI where we can uh provide params
see exactly what's happening and the
beauty of it is that we have uh real
time um display of the actions so we see
exactly what's happening at the that
point in time.
uh the WY it has uh open AI compatible
API
specifically with the responses uh uh
protocol is that there's implementation
for that and it makes easier our from
our code to talk to devi right because
there are different ways for you to you
could have for example in net we have
console apps where you have just um um
prints on UI but what we can do we can
have APIs with donets and then having a
way to connect uh with dev UI through
endpoints that's exactly what DevUI
provides to us there is support for open
telemetry like trace or observability
which is good because then we see
exactly what happened.
Uh this is recommended for development
only and should not be productionized
even because this is at preview. Uh and
things are changed on this space. Uh for
now devi
but things could could change on this
field. One thing that I noticed is that
if you look at at the beginning of the
year, all of this was simply preview and
now we have agent framework on on G8
right the part of the library but that
UI is still preview things could change
so it's something that you should not
use for production at all only for
development purposes
just looking here uh at the chats so
to see like how if there are like any
sort of questions.
Let's see.
Okay,
just checking here.
Yeah, there's a question here from Edge
Pereira where I think like maybe later
like maybe this could be showed like to
to the public, but what decision
framework should an org uh here you go.
What decision framework should an org
use to determine whether a use case
needs a single agent deterministic
workflow or a multi- aent workflow?
uh this one uh in terms of decision
framework uh I think like there are
different methodologies like because
this is not you could like look at this
like from a technical perspective but
what you would do is that you would have
your business requirements like any sort
of uh business functions and the process
really that happens in an organization
and then from there like as you have
mapped what happens with those business
processes then you convert them onto a
particular workflow depending on the
tasks that need to be executed. They
could be agentic
uh where you're bringing LLMs right for
uh these sort of open-ended challenges
or they could be just procedural uh
executions where you could have simply
just logic right so I say that like an
agent uh it's a logic with a a brain LLM
it has like tools all of that but when
you don't have that brain it's simply a
job so that's going to help you define
whether you need like a single agents
perhaps you need to have multiple agents
or how you're going to coordinate them.
If I talk about like a single um let's
say like a sequential the sequential
pattern that I have my screen things
could take like longer for executing
perhaps if you want to look at
performance you could make things to
work in in parallel so but to start
right so I think the decision comes from
business processes and then you evaluate
each step of this process it's simply
like a job or you need an agent to do
that sort of work and then how you
organize looking at performance or even
like the behavior uh and the challenges
of those uh problems that's where we
have like the other patterns group chats
magentic they're more uh they're
different from what the market has been
using for a long time I hope I have
answered your question but yeah uh so
just bring like those on and then I'll
have a look at them just continue here.
Uh I want to jump to code and what I'm
going to do in here is just uh
intercolate and transition from slides
to code and then just to show like uh
just as a teaser for you to see how it
works and how the code is structured as
well. But on the sequential pattern we I
explained that the tasks happen in in
sequence, right?
I'm not going to jump in here like to
explain this particular use case. I'm
going to jump to the codes and then we
can see exactly what's in there.
I have my zoomit in here. But this is
the sample I'm making available. Right?
So it's a Microsoft agentworkflows.net.
I put this for demonstration purpose.
Microsoft agent framework has
um their own uh repository. I did this
because of the session, right? So, I
just putting things together that make
sense for this uh presentation. But what
you're going to notice in here is that
we have oops we have different parts of
the solution in here where
we have three parts. The first one is
the simple one where uh I have all the
workflows all together. So you could
just run this one and see what happens.
And then I have the different uh
orchestrations split into a console.
This is a console or um uh UI web UI. Uh
it's basically an API and I have like a
shared library where I'm sharing tools
and we're going to see like how it works
and here's the complex one where really
diving onto the executors right uh as
framework abstracts has different
abstractions in here it's very simple in
here we go a little bit deeper and here
we it's hands on like I'll say like it's
full
We're going to go hands- on and
everything, but this is very detailed,
right? So, uh, but that's the structure
of the project. Let's go like to the
sequential and just to show what I have.
So, let me see. I think I'm going to
pull like a little bit bigger. That
should be okay. But we have three parts
of the code. All right. And let me show
like the sequential here. is that what I
have is this package
where everything happens right agents AI
workflows I have some the extensions as
well and I this is I would say kind of
in all
agent if you're using leverage agents
this is kind of standard you need depend
on where you're using OpenAI Azure you
kind of mix Yeah, but for the workflows
you need this agent agents AI workflows
and extensions AI as well which is kind
of if you're doing chats or uh not
workflows you also like get to use that
but that's what we have in here.
uh in terms of the solution we have
variables open AI endpoints deployment
name API keys and then we have our
agents after we set up that which is
coming from user secrets okay so I'm not
going to share my secrets in here but
I'm using user secrets as you have those
params then we can have those executions
you're going to see that uh imagine that
if we had agents controlling
uh aircraft takeoffs.
What we have here is is that we have a
runway scan agent that looks at any sort
of impediment, right? It's just to get
the thumbs up if like the surface
conditions are all good before
departure. We have a air traffic control
agent that looks or checks the output
from the runway scan agent and it says
okay responsive cleared or hold right so
it's going to allow or forbid the
departure and we have the pilot agent
that's going to put like the the engines
on hold right or not or it's going to
departure we have tools
And the tools in here they are um well
if I am to bring them so they're part of
the shared library but they are bringing
random decisions right. So it's going to
pick randomly a particular decision. So
things are going to be completely
dynamic.
We could get like a clear runway takeoff
uh or maybe we would be blocked. What
I'm going to do, I'm going to run the
code and I have like a break point. One
of the things with the agent framework
is that we have those rappers.
I say this is a wrapper because the only
thing we're are passing here are just
the agents. Okay, there's another agents
in there, but it's so simple that we
have build sequential. That's it. That's
going to do the work for us. We don't
need to dive into an extra level. Uh it
just like depending on what you want to
do, this might be enough really for you
to get going. What I have in here is
just like some helpers don't uh not not
of a concern, but what they doing is
that they taking they're printing to the
Y and we have like this to be run as a
stream. Let me pull like this one as uh
as a startup. And I'm gonna run that.
And we should we should be able to see
the
let's see here the debug
should start to some points.
Okay.
Yeah. Came up [laughter] first run.
Anyways, but I'm going to run this. I
have my console. I'm going to bring the
console in here as well. But as soon as
I trigger that, we should see some
behavior in here. And the UI the console
should display that to us. So like
there's a sequential workflow the runway
uh scan agent is saying that low debris
is spotted. So it's f it's running. So
we found like a impediment but it's
running those sensors and as I said
they're random. So they're just making
it uh validating things as it happens.
But when you look like there are like
hazards have been identified then we
have the air traffic control agent doing
oh look hold. Okay. So he made a
decision that okay nope. Uh based on the
conditions this is going to be on hold
and then in the end we have in here that
engines have been cut by the the pilot.
Okay. So we see that well one
output from the runway scan agents
served as input for
uh the air traffic control and then for
the pilots. So this is the sequential
way. What I want to do is just to
continue exploring the other patterns.
Right
in here we have the the concurrent where
we have those parallel. Let's see if I
might ponder why is it here that's the
fan out fan in right. So we have like a
coordinator and then things they kind of
branch and we have multiple agents in
execution. In the end we have
aggregation. So we can run them
simultaneously. They can work in
parallel. So this is one of one of the
performance uh indicators or to help us
to define like the total time. Perhaps
if you had the sequential it would take
like a longer periods. If you are if you
can make them run in parallel then you
can save time but it depends on the use
case. There are case where even though
you have mo many uh agents they need to
run in sequence because you're depending
on the outputs of others. So in this
case here we are saving time and we
using like this uh fan out fan in
pattern in here with the concurrent uh u
flow. Let's see this one with devi. All
right. So the first one we explored
on console the this one what we're going
to do is to explore with the web dev UI
for that one is going to be the
concurrent I'm going to put this one on
my
to start in here let's look at the codes
actually before that on the project
uh you're going to notice that we have
this guy here. Okay, this one is my
version that's in preview, but that's
the dev UI. So, we're bringing a nougat
package for it.
Similar structure that we have, but what
we do have in here is that we are
bringing devi as part of the pipeline,
right? The donet pipeline using service
collection. Not sure if I'm familiar
with that, but that's how we inject
instances of uh objects onto the donet
pipeline in here uh with the web API. Uh
same different parts, same as I said
like user secrets, variables, but then
we start uh hooking things onto the
service collection, right? So adding the
chat client and then we're adding those
agents and we have like similar behavior
like with similar structure with the
system message with tools right then the
same here. One interesting point is that
uh during the football world cup we were
doing
um
well that's when I produced like this
this demo and then what I put in here
it's a concurrent uh flow where
before like the sessions or the matches
can happen there are a lot of things
that could go wrong. All right. So with
power like safety if like there are like
any sort of hazards the stadium capacity
if things are anything that could go
wrong in here. What I I I did is just
putting putting all of those checks to
be executed right and to be validated.
So we have like a fields operations
agent that's going to check for stadium
lighting uh go structures everything
that related to the structure of the
field operations stadium safety agents
it's going to look emergency exits fire
suppression systems all of that medical
readiness agent so it's going to
validate their paramedics ambulance all
of that power systems agents. It's going
to check like power backup generators,
power supply, and we have the broadcast
systems as well. Verify if the broad the
cameras are all good. There's network
connectivity.
There are lots in here, right? So, but
what's important is that we're going to
get a validation whether it's ready or
if it's blocked, right? So, the match
can happen or not. I reckon like if that
was really to be the thing imagine if
they were to cancel a match that would
be [laughter]
that would be catastrophic right so but
in here we're trying to simulate what
could go wrong and because it's all
random things could go wrong in here uh
when we look at service collection now
is the important part with devi we're
hooking
okay all of that in here like devi even
the responses in here conversations they
belong to WUI. So we are WI has its own
abstraction that's going to take the
outputs
and display on on the UI for us. But
more importantly, we have the
well agent framework doing the heavy
lift. And when you look in here,
we have this I built concurrent. That's
a pretty good like abstraction.
That's where we're passing the different
agents, right? So you can see we have
those agents, all of them in here, but
they are passed in here. Okay. So, it's
Yeah, we're adding them onto the
pipeline. Let's run that and then we can
see what happens. I think I put this one
on my startup. Let me just run that.
That should open. Uh, let's see. That
should bring me.
Oops. When it does,
it's coming. Let me bring my console.
So, there is an endpoint here. 7,05.
I'm I'm on work. I'm working on let's
see on Chrome.
Uh should be this one. Cool. Uh
yeah, by the way, we have URLs and the
URLs are the ones where all of these oh
the contents that came like um that
helped me creating this session with
like Microsoft agent work framework
flows come from Microsoft learn and we
have the workflow orchestrations right
the ones I mentioned
and devi uh it's interesting on this
case. We're going to see
what it what it is the details in there.
But the C one there's there news in here
and that's something we can see that's
going to it's going to go to Aspire.
Okay. So there are things happening and
currently I don't have Aspire in here
but I can see that there will be updates
in here like soon for us.
What I need to do is that I need to
bring my URL and then I need to include
that. Oops. I need to include dev UI. If
I don't do that, nothing happens.
So, let me bring it.
Cool. So, that should be loaded. Yep.
And it's interesting that we have like
this UI where we can visualize the
different agents. So, I could talk to
those agents, right? and see like how
they what they're doing like what can
you do?
Uh this is for the broadcast systems
agent and I can talk to it. It's going
to say yeah I'm I'm just like the
broadcast systems agent for the workup.
I verify all the broadcasting stadium
communications. So you have those
details in here and there are different
parts like what you can see. So I just
click on this on this bubble. I can see
that I'm using GPT41 for it. Everything
it's in memory. I have my system prompt
remember like the ones or like on code
they're here. They're being displayed
and I have different tools. All right.
So all of those tools are the ones that
are randomly
being triggered and they provide
different sites.
We have uh well that's the conversation.
I can see the number of tokens. I think
I I can delete the current conversation,
start new ones. Uh I have the events in
here. I sent this message. There were
events that were triggered. Uh we don't
have like it's kind of limited. We don't
have like ways of sorting, ascending,
descending. But what you can see is that
it's descending. So we are having the
latest on top and we see what happened.
Right. So exactly traces and tools.
Okay. What I want to do is to trigger
the workflow. So, we have the workflow
in here.
Yeah, look at that. Well, I think if I
zoom in, I didn't create well, we all
connected with the build concurrent, but
agents framework created this and look
at that. If you look, we have executors.
So, remember the the building blocks. So
they are execute there are executors
doing the work for us. All right. So but
we didn't jump to it. So agent framework
has this abstraction and it can it is
doing that for us which is cool. Uh so
we don't need really to uh uh um
manipulate those executors.
um if you don't have like any
requirements to
I'm going to say like for example you
could do create the executors and
manipulate them if you really want to
have fine grain control okay uh I'm
going to show here on the complex um
soon uh the complex examples but yeah if
you want fine grain control then you use
executors but it adds additional degree
of complex XY but you can do that in in
have better control of what happens. Uh
what I want to do I want to copy the
prompt.
Uh I had opened the UI but my prompt is
on the console. I'm going to copy this
and then we can look together. So let me
just bring the UI again.
Here we go. And we're going to put like
this input in here. And that's like I'm
saying assess all the field operations,
stadium safety, medical readiness.
That's my prompt. That's my user prompt.
And when we trigger that, we're going to
see things happening. We're going to see
colors, right? Meaning that the agents
are in execution. When it gets green, it
means that the agents have finalized.
Let's trigger that. So we can see that
the agents are running or in parallel.
They are performing different actions.
We can see the events are being
triggered. They're growing. We can see
the colors that have been are being f or
are being they're being modified and
then all of a sudden we have everything
that happening here right
uh by looking here I would need to dig
and see exactly what happened at some
stage we should be able to see
uh one of the decisions we could see I
think this one is just here online fire
suppression online safe clearance denied
So I can see that things in here didn't
go like stage is not is not safe unsafe
and then okay yeah you have a way of
visualizing that under like the events
right at the same time because I had my
console you can see the colors in here
but every single color represents what
one agent is doing. So there was a
medical broadcast power uh system down
here, right? So yeah, you would say like
what what happened? So the broadcast PA
system is is down. So so what happens is
that uh no the match has been cancelled,
right? So that's not happening at all,
which is not good.
Uh but that's part of the fun.
uh and then we have the handoff
uh in here like on these three patterns
I'm going to explore on codes one of
them is just because it can be time
consuming but let's see all of the
concepts in here how they work and then
we jump to a a single case uh for the
case I think like the magentic one shows
um
um how the Handoff pattern is kind of in
there, right? Let's explore first the
the orchestrations.
And then we have the handoff. Where's my
laser point? And with the handoff
pattern, what happens is that we have
this conditional
uh routing by between specialists.
So what happens like for example this
triage agent? So imagine that we have a
customer service and we're talking to
their supports. We could have like a
distriage agent that verifies
the request and if the person is saying
that for example that being built twice
for a particular service the agent would
have the would be smart enough because
it has prompt to decides whether to uh
hand it over to a billing fraud or the
technical team because like let's Say if
you're if you have a subscription but
you have been build twice you wouldn't
be fraud. It wouldn't be a technical
issue would be like a billing concern an
issue. So the triage assist agent would
hand it over to a billing agent to sort
things do a refund of the the
duplication or the payment that was made
like in duplication. If there was
something suspicious, something could be
fraudulent, the agents could would hand
it over to the fraud agent. If the
person is saying that's trying to submit
something on the the website, e-commerce
for example, there's an error on the
page or so that would be more like a
technical issue. So the agents could
triage another agent. But what it does
that this coordinator has the knowledge
to hand it over to specialists right and
with that all of the context is managed
by agent framework so we don't need to
manage that agent framework does that
for us but it it says here the context
passed selectively to the next agent
right so it's not going to be passed to
the agents that don't have any concern
about that issue
Then we have the group chats, right? So
that's another orchestration pattern
where the agents collaborate in a shared
conversation.
Right? So when it says in here a shared
conversation is that they're going to
take turns and there is a coordinator
that tells look it's your time to say
something and depending what he does the
coordinator would just pass to the other
agents right in general like you have
there are different ways routing in
general like that every single agent has
uh
a particular time or a particular turn
to come and provide some input or just
pass the turn for another agent if what
was discussed was not of the concern of
the agent.
But for example in here that there's uh
as if you were to have you're creating
like a paper uh a university paper for
example and then like we're calling this
like a builder but would be the students
but the students trigger this this
workflow to create a paper for and then
we have like this builder that would
take the inputs from a user for example
the user would submit to a coordinator
the coordinator would say look this is
the context. This is what was being
provided by the user. The builder would
start creating like a paper. Then the
builder finishes. Then coordinator pass
to the the next one in line rounding for
example where there's a critic that
would provide some out um feedback and
then with the feedback there could be
like it could ask for uh input from
researcher. So this one it wouldn't be a
concern of the reviewer. The reviewer
would just be passing to the researcher
and the would be cycles of this running.
Okay. So this could run like it just
depends on how you have defined the
could be random could be round robbing.
But what's important here is that
they're taking turns all the
participants in here. What's important
is that you need to have termination
rules in here.
Um termination rules could be something
uh that would be the language like
natural language where depending on what
let's say the reviewer the final
reviewer could say that yeah this is
looks great it's approved right or for
for me the terminology approve could be
the natural language that would be
passed to the coordinator and the
coordinator would have a prompt to
identify has been approved. Yes. Finish.
Terminate the flow. Uh there are cases
for those open-ended problems where the
you could define iterations, right? And
they would spin until you get uh they
get to resolve the issue or not, right?
So it's a a new pattern. So but you have
like you need to specify termination
rules
otherwise you might incur in burning
tokens
and then you pay the price. So and this
is the magentic pattern where
it's a if you look in here
it kind of resembles like the handoff
pattern but a little bit smarter. Uh I
would say it's just like that the hundi
is great. It's just like doesn't have
that sort of complexity uh embedded
because uh you don't need like that sort
of decision uh that's made with this
manager. But what happens is that this
manager he defines a plan dispatch for
the specialists
and based on the outputs of these
specialists it adapts and evolves the
plan. Okay. So this is more like a um
yeah
this is to be used like for complex
problems and where you need really to
evolve based on what you got is that you
review the the plan that needs to be uh
modified and then you have like another
action and everything here we call like
the task ledger where the history really
makes like a a difference on the
decisions and you you see like the
manager can ask uh for like a human. So
there's a human in the loop. You could
just say that ah look uh the man manager
could say uh this here is the plan. Are
you fine with it? Do you want to
improve? So you could have like this
this human in the loop to validate the
plan and then approve and then the
manager would just dispatch to the
specialist, right? So it does that and
replans at each step. So the special is
report back to the manager and that can
it can adapt best for open-ended
multi-step problem solving. So this one
it's a uh it's um
I would say the magentic it's a combines
the sort of hand off with uh planning
and
this concept in here with the manager
right that's not only a coordinator it
really makes the decision and evolves u
uh the the flow based on on those
outputs from the different specialists.
Let's go to the code. Okay. And for this
one, uh, let's go with the magentic.
Let me close that. And that magentic.
I'm going to do the console. The console
is
complex enough to
to approach with the web UI. We don't we
don't see it, right? You need to dig
through the traces. So it helps assists
you visualizing what's going on during
development but when you need to dig
onto the telemetry open telemetry yeah
it can be too much okay but up to you
like I prefer combining both where I can
view or visualize what's happening and
with devi seeing like how things are
connecting then jumping back to a
console and seeing the outputs okay
But it's yeah it's just like a personal
preference. Everyone has a different
view on that. And with the magentic
right the programming here similar
structure variables and we're creating
agents. Okay. But then uh you're going
to see that's kind of complex because
imagine this uh as um a security
incident. Okay. So if a when a security
incident happens, we have this
commander. The commander's orchestrator
is the manager. So the the manager is
going to say, "Look, there there's been
a security incident. We're going to be
triggering uh some analysis, right? So I
have my commander and the prompts for
that.
But what he knows, he knows that we have
specialists. We have a identity
specialist, a network specialist,
endpoint analyst specialist, a threat
intelligence and a sock analyst. All of
them they have different concerns. Okay,
different tools in here. Remember all
the tools here are they generate random
output.
But we have different concerns in here,
different specialists.
What's nice is that well agent framework
is kind of bringing a way for us to hook
them
uh a little bit better if uh we're going
to jump straight away to the complex
scenario. But in here it starts getting
a little bit more complicated but we
have a wrapper the magentic workflow
builder and then we're passing the
agents. Oops here. Okay. And one thing
require plan sign off. True. So I am the
human in the loop. I will need to
approve this plan otherwise nothing
happens. Um you need to have some guard
rails like for example the number of
rounds things could spin out of control
if like for those open-ended problem. So
you need to have better control for like
finalize and terminate the the flow if
you needed if things get like for stalls
things don't happen if you need to reset
so there wasn't an agreement or things
evolved to the wrong direction but
things could happen right so you need to
have uh a plan for terminating when
things don't work as expected I put like
this one uh startup and I'm going to run
Okay, I don't have break points but
intent to trigger this and then we can
see that I'm the human in the loop and I
should be
open. Let me close that.
I should be able to approve that.
So I have this one. So there's a cyber
security incident. That's what's being
provided in here. And it say that each
agent specialist gets two terms. Okay.
first to surface raw findings. Second to
cross reference things. So here it has
the magentic plan. Okay, magentic plan.
So it's proposing a plan for me and then
okay yeah going to bring the identity
specialist going to do this network
agent endp point. Okay based like adjust
investigation as new evidence emerges.
Please enter to approve or type feedback
to request a revision. I could say look
include like more details about I don't
know fires look at these particular
instances but for the demo yeah I'm
going to approve I just entered and what
we should see here start seeing the
tools right the callers
being displayed because the agents are
working right
at some stage we should have uh uh
feedback or some sort of analysis a
reporting of what happened. So looking
here network IP reputation logically
residential data payload loaded to fish
proxy attacker second logging has no VPN
session look like fishing domain
resolved before incident so there like
some different tools being triggered
that's going to provide as inputs for
the decision making browser extension
suspicious extension installed minutes
before the incident so imagine like that
there was a cyber cured uh events like
in here it's saying that like
an extension a browser extension that
has been compromised right so we have
some flags happening here and what we
should have is that a decision in the
end okay I'm going to let this one
running and then we should be able to
see it I I still want to show the
complex one let me just come back.
Let's see this one. Okay.
Uh because we have the executor. In the
executor, we have a base class and
that's where you have fine control.
Okay. So, you could implement your own
executors. They have like an infire.
They are typed. Let me bring my laser
point. The types you have a life cycle.
When we look at them, there are many of
them.
uh I'm not going to jump onto the
details but executors can have an input
input output there can be reflection
this one it's been deprecated but it's
been there for evaluating uh dynamically
like the um inputs output
with states
using like in chats okay uh I'm going to
show the example
in here is there of the complex
uh here. Okay,
remember like the stadium validation in
the check, right? So the match can occur
or not. We have those executors
dispatchers dispatchers exe field. But
let's look at here the create method.
Well, it's a it has like implementation.
It has the inputs, it has the outputs,
but I don't have we don't have the brain
here. We don't have LLMs. So, it's just
a wrap around logic where I'm validating
if it's a user or not depending on the
role. But it's just a job, right? So, an
executor here perform a job for me, but
has nothing to do with AI. But this one,
the medical, it does. Can you see? Like
we have a chat client. So, when I jump
to that, they're exactly the same. But
in here we have look at here the handle
we have the eye agents okay
[clears throat]
I have my prompts I have my tools I have
my session
I'm controlling this the executor is
basically a wrapper okay is a so you
could do you have full control you could
uh inject logging put like other sort of
validations logic in here okay so it
gives you flexibility right so It's
interesting that it's something that for
production workloads you might end up
getting to this because it gives you
flexibility to modify the logic for it.
Okay. So that's something it's more like
for your your awareness knowing that's
in there and then you can explore.
Let's see if like the prompt or the
agent finalize. It did. It did finish
incident report reports. Okay. So, we
have that
start confirmed there. There's been like
impact session hijacking. So, it has
after all of what happened
based on the tools that we had
identified there was a session hijacking
and it's bringing all of the reporting
for that. Okay. Evidence. you grab like
the outputs from the different
specialists recommended immediate uh
actions. So I have like everything here
like to provide a report and the
magentic workflow is just matched like
my requirements in here which is good
because uh that that was a complex
problem that need like insights and a
dynamic view of okay the different
variables that was just thrown along the
way to the manager
with that. Uh that's like the key
takeaways that you pick like the shape
that fits your workloads. You can
combine them and build like your
workflows, your orchestrations
composing like those patterns. If you
know like the executors, you have better
control, fine grain control on your
logic. One of the things in here is that
this is the QR codes for the repository.
I invite you to jump in there. If you're
using GitHub, just leave a star. I
appreciate. Yeah. And
I think with that, I'm just finishing
the the session. And just if you have
questions, we can look at them.
[snorts]
Let's see.
Okay. Let's see. Thank you. Um
save
edge how is accountability there's a
message from edge uh edge bera uh how's
account accountability maintained when
several agents collectively produce one
outcome any practice recommendations we
should start using
yeah on this one I think like there's as
part of your development you should
evaluate
the prompts
uh is just because you want to have some
guard rails
to check like if the answer that's been
produced matches
the intent the initial intent we didn't
explore in here but there are like ways
for you to evaluate
prompts different techniques even in the
net space there are like libraries to
help with that in general you
lot of them in Python. But as part of
your practice before like launching
bring those agents, you should have some
uh validation and have like valuations
to check whether you're getting the
outputs if they match your original
intent. Right? I think that hopefully
that's helped with some answers. Uh
Edge, let's see.
Uh let's say we build workflows like
this to a legal office. How can
sensitive data be prevented from flowing
to an agent that does not need it? Is it
possible? So there's a library now that
with the donet uh it's usually like for
harness and what happens is that there
are different guard rails in there where
you can even control if PII information
should be passed as part of the context
or not. So you just control through
parameters and then you need to specify
look PII information should be ignored
completely. Right? So that's how you do
it. in net there's a library I think
it's harness.ai AI following exactly the
same path but you you you can just find
that in Google. Uh so that's something
that I think the the Microsoft agent
framework team has been working on.
There are additional libraries for that.
I didn't put on this this example but
it's available for you to use.
I think with that all the questions
have been uh validated.
I'm not sure if Isabelle if you're
coming to the session or not but just in
case if the the reactor team doesn't
come like to thank you uh for being part
of the session and be in touch. I share
like all of the details at the beginning
of the session and yeah uh very happy to
know like what you've been doing and
understand like your challenges. So I
perhaps you help me preparing some use
cases where I can approach with the
technical community or even if you are
interested we can chat and then we can
align a session with you as well on my
uh the user group uh I lead. Yeah.